- 잘 잤어?
- 안녕
-Morning.
-Hi.
데이트 어땠어?
How was your date?
- 꽤 좋았어
- 잘 됐네
-Pretty good.
-Oh, good.
My God. Sorry about that.
이런, 미안해요
그래, 아주 좋았어
Okay, really good.
나 가야 돼, 늦었어
I gotta go. I'm late.
나더러 저 여자랑
같이 있으라고?
You're going to leave
her with me?
걱정 마
끝내주는 여자야
Don't worry,
she's a terrific girl.
부탁 하나만 하자
Can you do me a favor?
난 심각한 관계 싫어한다고
좀 해주면 정말 고맙겠어
Could you mention I'm not looking
for a relationship? That'd be great.
뭐, 농담 마
What, are you kidding?
그냥 슬쩍 흘려
딴 얘기하다가
Just casually slip it in, you know.
Lay the groundwork.
난 고독을 즐기는 애라고
Tell her I'm a loner.
No, an outlaw.
나 같은 애와 엮여봐야
좋을 것 없다고 해
She doesn't want to get mixed up
with the likes of me.
그걸 다 기억하라고?
That's a lot to remember.
그냥 널 나쁜놈이라고
하면 안될까?
Can't I tell her that you're a pig?
나중에 내가 전화할거야
I'm gonna call her later myself.
정말이야
Honest.
챈들러는 해줬다구
여자한테 팬케이크도 만들어주고
Chandler used to do it.
He'd make her pancakes.
넉넉히 만들어서
내 거도 남겨두고
He'd make extras
and leave them for me.
난 아무 말 안해
내 일도 아닌데 뭐
I'm not telling her anything.
It's not my responsibility.
좋아
Fine.
그래도 팬케이크는
만들어 줄 거지?
Now, where did we land
on those pancakes?
- 안녕하세요
-Hi.
미안해요,
문이 안 잠겨서요
Sorry, but I couldn't get
that lock to work.
네, 내가 이사 왔을 때
조이가 고장냈어요
Yeah, Joey kind of disabled it
when I moved in.
- 레이첼이군요, 에린이에요
- 반가워요
-You must be Rachel. I'm Erin.
-Hi.
유치하게 들리겠지만
조이가 내 얘기하던가요?
I don't mean this to sound like high
school, but did he talk about me?
팬케이크 먹을래요?
Would you like some pancakes?
The One With Ross's Library Book
'대학 도서관'
- 여긴 왜 온 거야?
- 좋아, 맞춰 봐
-Come on. Why are we here?
-Okay, okay, take a guess.
예쁜 여학생들?
The hot chicks?
좋아, 도서관 컴퓨터에
이름을 검색해 봤거든
Okay, okay, I was typing names
into the library computer earlier...
재미 삼아서
you know, for fun.
내 이름을 쳤더니
뭐가 나왔게?
And I typed mine in,
and guess what came up?
내 박사학위 논문
My doctoral dissertation.
이 대학에서 제일 큰
도서관에 있다고
It's right down here in the biggest
library in the university.
와, 기분 좋겠는데
Wow, that's actually pretty cool.
There's also a book here
by a woman named Wendy Bagina.
그리고 여기 웬디 버자이나란
여자의 책도 있어
What is that?
무슨 소리야?
Sounds like two people are really
enjoying the Dewey decimal system.
누가 도서관에서
재미보고 있는 것 같은데
We're so sorry.
죄송합니다
You didn't bring me here to do that,
did you?
저러자고 여기 날
데려온 건 아니지?
She sent the chicken back again?
치킨을 또 돌려보냈어?
너무 팍팍하다면서
직접 얘기하겠대요
She said it's too dry and wants
to explain to you how she wants it.
어디 치킨 전문가 좀 볼까
I'd like to meet this chicken expert.
들여보내
Send the colonel in.
말도 안 돼!
Oh, my God!
넌 억세게 운좋다
Lucky bastard.
- 재니스
- 반가워요
-Janice.
-How are you...
멋진 레스토랑에서
치킨 요리 잘하는 주방장님?
Ms. Hotshot-Chef-at-the-Big-Fancy-
Restaurant-With-the-Best-Chicken-Ever?
반가워요
I'm fine.
손가락에 그게 뭐예요?
눈이 멀 지경이네
Oh, what is that on your finger?
I'm blind.
요리만 잘 하는 게
아니었나봐
So who's the lucky guy?
말도 안 돼
Oh, my God.
미안해, 자기
I am so sorry, sweetie.
괜찮아?
Are you okay?
You didn't tell her we're engaged?
우리 약혼했단 말
안 했지?
-She saw the ring.
-Did she freak out?
- 반지를 봤는 걸
- 놀라 자빠지던?
She was shocked,
but then again, so were most people.
충격받은 것 같던데
누군들 안 그랬나?
She actually has a boyfriend herself.
재니스도 남자친구 생겼대
Name's Clark.
이름은 클락이고
She also invited herself
to our wedding.
우리 결혼식에도
오고 싶대
Clark too.
클락하고
You said no, right?
안 된다고 했지?
She cornered me. She asked me
if the wedding was in town.
어쩔 수 없었어, 뉴욕에서
식 올리냐고 묻잖아
-What was I supposed to do?
-Lie.
- 뭐라고 말해?
- 거짓말 하지
How hard is that?
"Your check's in the mail."
그게 뭐 어렵다고?
'수표 보냈습니다'
"Oh, your baby's so cute."
'아가 귀엽네요'
"I can't wait to read your book, Ross."
'네 책 기대된다, 로스'
So she comes to the wedding.
Maybe it won't be so bad.
결혼식에 오면 어때?
괜찮을 거야
Think she'll sit quietly?
Think she'll want to make a toast?
조용히 앉아 있을까?
건배하자고 하면 어쩌지?
You don't think she'll want
to sing "Part-Time Lover"?
'파트타임 러버' 부른다고
하면 어쩔 거지?
Oh, my God. She's not gonna like
the chicken either, is she?
맙소사, 치킨도
맛없다고 하겠네?
아냐, 괜찮아
You know what? It'll be okay.
어쩌면 안 올지도 모르지
She's probably not gonna even
want to come.
- 그럴까?
- 아니, 거짓말이야
-Really?
-No, that was a lie.
얼마나 쉬워?
See how easy that was?
자기라면 거짓말
했을 거라고?
So you would have just lied?
물론이지
Yes.
- 정말 그렇게 쉬웠을까?
- 그럼
-It would have really been that easy?
-Yes.
토요일에 또 해, 그 둘과
저녁 약속 있으니까
Do it Saturday. We're having
dinner with her and Clark.
Hey, what's up?
- 뭐하냐?
- 어서 와
친구가 와 있네?
Hey, who's your friend?
- 안녕, 조이
- 에린
-Hey, Joey.
-Erin.
아직 안 갔네요
You're still here.
그냥 하루 종일
재미있게 보냈어
We ended up spending the day together
and had such a great time.
그랬구나, 에린 괜찮지
Why wouldn't you? Erin is great.
너희들보다 낫지
And then there's you guys.
나 가봐야겠어요
Well, listen, I better get going.
너무 재밌었어요, 고마워요
Today was great. Thanks.
조이, 어제 즐거웠어요
And Joey, last night was fun.
전화할게요
Yeah. I'll call you.
- 나도 전화할게요
- 아님 내가 하던가
-I'll call you too.
-Or I'll call you.
- 전화해요
- 그래요
-And call me.
-Okay.
Good to see you again.
반가웠어요
-Bye-bye.
-Bye.
- 안녕
The system kind of broke down, huh?
도대체 어떻게 된 거야?
Joey, I'm sorry. I just couldn't
tell her all those things.
미안해, 그런 얘길
할 수가 없어서
And we got to talking, and I..
그냥 얘길 하다 보니...
We want you to marry her.
너 쟤랑 결혼해라
What?
뭐?
She is so amazing. You have no idea.
넌 모르겠지만
너무 멋진 여자야
Who do you think brought her here?
누가 데려왔는데?
Cupid.
큐피드
She's so cool.
She speaks four languages.
너무 멋져
4개 국어를 한대
Man, do you know what guys want.
그래 남자들
거기에 껌뻑 죽지
Come on, she's so perfect for you.
She's sweet.
정말 완벽한 여자야
너무 착하고
She likes baseball.
She had two beers at lunch.
야구도 좋아하고
점심때 맥주도 두 병 마시고
My beers?!
내 맥주를?
Look, she's a very nice girl.
아주 좋은 여자야
We had a very good time,
but I don't see it going anywhere.
나도 즐거웠지만
장래가 없다니까
You always say that.
넌 항상 그렇게
말하잖아
Maybe if you gave her a chance,
it would go somewhere.
네가 기회를 주면
잘 될 수도 있잖아
I'm sorry, you guys.
I just don't think so.
미안하지만
그렇겐 안 돼
-Whatever.
-Fine.
- 맘대로 해
- 좋아
Hey, don't start judging me.
날 비난하지 마
You're in love with your assistant.
비서와 사랑에
빠진 주제에
You're sleeping with the guy
who keeps pigeons on the roof.
넌 지붕에서 비둘기
키우는 남자 좋아하고
Phoebe!
피비!
Secret affair.
비밀이랬잖아
'센트럴 퍼크'
내 책 앞에서
그 짓을 하다니
People are doing it
in front of my book.
I'm sorry?
뭐라고?
My doctoral dissertation is in the
library at school. I went to see it.
도서관에 내 박사논문이
있어서 보러 갔는데
And there were students making babies
right in the paleontology section.
고생물학 도서 섹션에서
학생들이 아기 만들고 있잖아
Oh, my God.
Did you get to see anything good?
맙소사
그래서 제대로 좀 봤어?
너희 학교에도
At your school...
학생들이 그런 짓
잘 하는데 있었어?
was there a place on campus
where students went to fool around?
그럼 있었지
Yeah, there was.
아무도 안 보는 책이
꽂힌 도서관 구석이지
In the corner of the library where all
the books were that nobody ever read.
그래, 맞아
Yes, there was.
사람들이 자꾸 오는데
거기 뭐 있나 봐
Great, because people kept showing up.
I think it's like a thing.
잠깐만
Hold on a second.
5층 구석 벽 쪽 말야?
Fifth floor, against that back wall?
내가 말을 말지!
Oh, for crying out loud!
- 영화보러 가야지
- 급할 거 뭐 있어?
-So we should go catch our movie.
-What's the rush?
난 예고편 보는 게 좋아
I'd like to see the previews.
사탕 사먹는게 좋아
The candy.
- 안녕
- 와, 이게 누구신가
-Oh, hey.
-Well, look who's here.
- 안녕, 조이
- 안녕, 에린
-Hey, Joey.
-Hey, Erin.
- 안녕, 레이첼
- 어서 와요
-Hey, Rachel.
-Hi.
우린 영화보러
가려던 참인데
We were about to take off
and see a movie.
- 이걸 어째!
- 왜 그래?
-Oh, no!
-What's wrong?
피비, 우리 파티에
가야 되잖아
Phoebe, we forgot that party
we have to go to.
이런
Oh, no.
무슨 파티?
What party?
- 생일 파티
A birthday party.
누구 생일 파티?
Whose birthday party?
Alison's birthday party.
- 앨리슨 생일 파티
And how old is Alison?
앨리슨이 몇 살인데?
Thirty-two.
- 서른 두 살
Wait a minute.
Why don't you guys do something?
잠깐, 두 사람 같이
시간 보내면 되겠네
그러게, 너무 잘 됐네
Look how that worked out.
이봐요,
나 이 학교 교수인데요
Excuse me. Hi, I'm a professor here.
5층 437열, 고생물 도서
섹션 알아요?
Do you know the paleontology section,
fifth floor, stack 437?
그럼요
5분만 기다려요
Well, yes.
Just give me five minutes.
나 대신 일할
사람 좀 찾고요
I just have to find someone
to cover my shift.
그런게 아니에요
No, no, no.
책임자 좀 불러줘요
Can I speak to someone in charge?
무슨 일이죠?
How can I help?
안녕하세요
고생물 도서 섹션에
Hi, I was wondering, is it possible
to increase security...
경비 좀 강화할 수 없어요?
in the paleontology section?
제 책이 거기 있거든요
I wrote a book that's up there.
그런데 읽지는 않고
사람들이...
And instead of reading it,
people are...
그 앞에서 뒹굴고
있지 뭡니까?
Well, they're rolling around
in front of it.
무슨 말씀인지
잘 알고 있습니다만
We are aware of the problem
you're referring to.
도서관 직원이
충분치가 않아서요
As far as increasing security,
I'm afraid the library's understaffed.
못 도와드리겠네요
I can't help you.
그럼, 좋아요
Well, fine.
책에 대한 존경심을
가진 사람이
If I'm the only person
with any appreciation...
나 뿐이라면 나라도
직접 감시하겠어요
of the sanctity of the written
word, then I'll go defend it myself.
따라오지 말아요
Don't you follow me.
- 에린하곤 어땠어?
- 죽여줬어
-How did it go with Erin?
-Unbelievable.
정말 재미있었어
We had the best time.
- 이제 화 안난 거야?
- 아냐, 너희들이 옳았어
-So you're not mad anymore?
-No, no. You guys were totally right.
첫 데이트 때보다
훨씬 좋았어
This was much better than
the first date.
그 땐 둘 다
좀 어색했거든
It was awkward.
We were both nervous.
- 둘이 같이 잤잖아
- 그러고 나니 진정되더라
-Didn't you sleep together?
-Yeah, that calms me down.
공통점도 정말 많고
And we have so much in common.
샌드위치, 스포츠 좋아한대
메츠 팬인게 좀 그렇지만
She loves sandwiches, sports.
Although she is a Met fan.
지금은 괜찮은데
애라도 낳으면...
Not an issue now,
but if we had kids...
맙소사, 지금
애 얘기하고 있잖아
Oh, my God! Listen to you talking
about having kids.
와, 조이
Oh, my Joey.
나보다 먼저 결혼하진 마
Please don't get married before I do.
I just cannot believe
that Clark stood me up.
클락이 날 바람맞추다니
He may still show up.
올 거야
What are you, stupid?
무슨 멍청한 소리야?
-It's been three hours.
-Is that all?
- 3시간이 넘었어
- 겨우?
신나는 얘기해요
Let's go on to happier things.
결혼식 얘기 좀 해 줘요
Why don't you tell me
about your lovely wedding.
안 그래도 결혼식 때문에
할 얘기가 있어
There was something that we wanted
to tell you about the wedding.
조촐하게 할 거거든
It's going to be a small ceremony.
아주 소박하게
Tiny.
왜 하나 싶을
정도로 말야
We're not even sure
why we're having it.
가족들끼리만
모일 거거든
It's actually going to be just family.
잠깐만
Oh, wait.
그럼 날 가족으로
생각하는 거야?
You two think of me as family?
그럼 한 가지 물어볼 테니
솔직히 대답해 줘요
I have to ask you something now,
and be honest.
축가는 '케어리스 위스퍼'
'레이디 인 레드' 어느 거?
Do you want me to sing
"Careless Whisper" or "Lady in Red"?
무슨 소릴? 메츠엔 변변한
마무리 투수도 없는데
How can you say that?
The Mets have no closer.
- 베니테즈는요?
- 시리즈 첫 게임 생각 안 나요?
-What about Benitez?
-What about game one of the series?
- 입 다무는 거 어때요?
- 그쪽이나 다물어요
-What about shut up?
-You shut up.
말싸움 너무 재밌다
I love arguing with her.
- 잠깐 실례
- 그래
-Be right back.
-Okay.
조이완 잘 돼가요?
How's it going with Joey?
그럭저럭요
Oh, okay.
그럭저럭?
Okay?
좋아하잖아요
조이 좋아하죠?
Tell me that you like him, please.
I mean, tell me that you like him.
좋은 사람인데
잘 될 것같진 않아요
He's a really great guy, and I know
you really want this to work out...
미래가 안 보이거든요
but I just don't see this
having a future.
좋아한다고 하더니
어떻게 된 거죠?
But you said that you liked him.
What happened?
그새 마음이 변했어요?
Did you just change your mind?
- 네, 조금
- 그럼 다시 바꿔요
-Kind of.
-Then change it back!
미안하지만
불꽃이 안 튀어요
I'm sorry.
It's just, there's no real spark.
같이 자지 않았어요?
Didn't you sleep together?
그랬죠
Yeah.
헤프긴
Tramp.
조이도 알아요?
Does Joey have any idea?
아마 모를 걸요
부탁이 있어요
I don't think he does.
You know what?
조이한테 심각한
관계는 별로라고
Maybe you could tell him
I'm not interested...
좀 전해줄래요?
in a serious relationship.
고독을 즐기는
타입이라고요?
You mean, like,
that you're kind of a loner?
네, 그게 좋겠어요
Yeah, that'd be great.
- 그리고 댁이 '스트론조'라고요?
- 뭐라고요?
And maybe that you're a real stronzo.
I'm sorry.
4개 국어에 이태리어는
안 들어가나 보죠
I guess Italian isn't one
of the four languages you speak.
- 갈래?
- 그래, 가자
-Hey. Want to go?
-Yeah, let's go.
- 그럼 또 봐
- 잘 가요
-Okay. See you guys later.
-Bye, guys.
고마워
Hey, thank you so much.
와
Wow.
에린을 데려온 게
큐피드가 아니었군
I guess it wasn't cupid
that brought her here.
그냥 평범한
날아다니는 난장이였나봐
No, just a regular old flying dwarf.
네? 도와 드릴 일이라도?
Yes, yes. How can I help you?
아뇨, 둘러보고 있어요
We were just looking around.
아, 학자 양반이시군
Oh, you're fellow scholars.
정확히 뭘 둘러보고 있죠?
What exactly were you looking for?
체스터 박사의 검치호에
대한 명상이라도
Perhaps Dr. Chester Stock's
musings...
찾고 계시나?
on the Smilodon californicus?
당장 꺼져!
Get out of here!
누구 기다려요?
Meeting someone?
아님 매리엄의
Or are you just here to brush up...
진화에 대한 관점에 대해
관심이 있나요?
on Merriam's views on evolution?
제 생각에 매리엄의 관점은
지나치게 진보적인데요
Actually, I find Merriam's views
far too progressionist.
나도 그렇다고 생각해요
I find Merriam's views
far too progressionist.
죄송하지만 누구시죠?
I'm sorry. Who are you?
난 이 학교 교수
로스 겔러예요
I'm a professor here. Ross Geller.
로스 겔러?
귀에 익은 이름인데
Ross Geller? Why do I know that name?
It's a...
잠깐만요
Wait.
이거 쓰신 분인가요?
Did you write this?
맞아요
Yes.
그럼 그쪽이 내 책을
대출했던 사람이에요?
You're the person
who checked out my book?
제가 생각했던 것과
많이 다르네요
You know, you look nothing
like I would have thought.
너무 젊으세요
You're so young.
4학년 월반했거든요
Well, I skipped fourth grade.
정말, 정말 죄송합니다
I am very, very sorry.
- 데이트 어땠어?
- 좋았어, 산책도 좀 하고
-So how was your date?
-Great. We walked around the Village.
아이스크림 가게에 가서
쉐이크 사서 나눠먹고
We went to this ice cream place.
Split a milk shake.
7대 3이었지만
Seventy-thirty, but still.
어디 조용한 데로 같이
여행갈까 생각 중이야
I'm thinking of taking her upstate
to one of those bed and breakfasts.
그래? 같이 가겠대?
Really? She said she wants to go?
놀래켜 줄거야, 일이
바쁘대서 좀 그렇지만
No, it's a surprise. It's gonna be
tricky, because she's busy at work.
좋아, 조이
얘기 좀 하자
Joey, look, honey,
we need to talk, okay?
내가 받은 느낌인데
I got the feeling from her...
에린은 심각한 관계
별로인 것 같던데
that she's not looking
for a serious relationship.
- 왜 그런 생각을 해?
- 에린이 그랬거든
-Where are you getting this?
-She told me.
고독을 즐기는 사람이래
She said she's kind of a loner.
- 조이...
- 아냐, 괜찮아
-Joey..
-Hey, Rach, it's cool, you know.
나도 혼자 지내는 거
좋아하잖아
I'm a loner too, right?
조이, 있지?
넌 그 여자한테 과분해
Hey, Joey. You know what?
You are way too good for her.
다음엔 네가 시키는 대로
꼭 얘기해 줄게
I promise, next time I will tell them
you're not looking for a relationship.
아냐, 그러지 마
No, don't do that. Just...
- 그냥 날 정말 좋아하는가 봐 줘
- 그래, 그것도
-Next time, make sure she likes me.
-Well, that too.
조이?
Joey?
- 팬케이크 좀 줄까?
- 언제 말하나 했다
-Do you want some pancakes?
-Finally.
어쩌면 좋지?
What are we gonna do?
'케어리스 위스퍼'가
나을 것 같아
I say we go with "Careless Whisper."
챈들러?
Chandler?
우리 본 것 같아?
우리 봤어?
Did she see us yet? Did she see us?
재니스, 무슨 일이죠?
Janice, what are you doing here?
집에 돌아가려고 했는데
I thought I was gonna go back
to my apartment...
오늘 밤은 정말
혼자 있기 싫었어요
but I just felt like I really
couldn't be alone tonight.
오늘 여기서 자면
안 될까 해서요
I was just wondering if I could maybe
stay here with you.
가족과 함께 있고
싶거든요
Just, I really feel like I need
to be with family.
우리 애들이 재니스 이모라고
부르는 거 아냐?
Our kids are gonna call her
Aunt Janice, aren't they?
부탁해요, 안 그럼 나도
무슨 짓을 할지 몰라서
Please. Because otherwise,
I really don't know what I might do.
알고 싶진 않고?
Aren't you just a teensy bit curious?
- 티슈 있어요?
- 네, 화장실에요
-You have any tissues?
-Yeah, in the bathroom.
자고 가라고 해
We'll just let her stay.
안 돼, 한 번 자면
계속 있으려고 할 걸
No. If we let her stay,
she will stay forever.
- 자기 안락의자처럼
- 지금 그 생각하고 있어?
-Kind of like your Barcalounger.
-Is that what you're thinking about?
하루도 생각 안 한적 없어
I never stop thinking about it.
Hey, you guys?
나 목욕하기 전에
화장실 쓸래요?
Do either one of you want to get
in there before I take my bath?
재니스, 미안하지만
Janice, I'm sorry...
오늘 못 재워주겠어요
but you can't stay here tonight.
왜요?
Why not?
솔직히 말할까요?
Honestly?
우리 아파트엔
Our apartment is a hotbed...
전자파가 세거든
for electromagnetic activity.
모니카와 난 면역이 됐지만
Monica and I have been immunized,
but sadly...
재니스는 아니잖아
you have not.
이불이 있어야겠네
I'm gonna need a comforter.
알러지 방지이불 있어요?
안 그럼 코가 막혀서요
Do you have a hypoallergenic one?
Because otherwise I get very nasal.
고양이 있어요?
벌써 코가 막히네
Do you have a cat?
Because it's already happening.
들었어요? 들어봐요
Do you hear that? Listen.
이런, 맙소사
재니스 제발 가줘요
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
You have to go.
왜요?
Why?
챈들러가 아직 재니스에게
감정이 남아있어요
Because Chandler still has
feelings for you.
그래요?
He does?
뭐라고?
Say again?
맞아, 그래
That's right. That's right.
그래서 오늘
못 재워주는 거예요
And that is why you can't
stay here tonight.
그리고 결혼식에도
오면 안 되고요
And probably why you shouldn't come
to the wedding.
감정이 많이 남아 있거든
Feelings. Such strong feelings.
어쩌면 그 감정은 영원히
사라질 순 없지만
I mean, I realize that his feelings
may never completely go away...
재니스는 갈 수 있잖아요
but you can.
맙소사
Oh, my God.
알았어요, 미안해요
I understand. I am so sorry.
갈게요
I'll go.
안녕, 모니카
Goodbye, Monica.
두 사람 평생
행복하게 살아요
I wish you a lifetime
of happiness with him.
챈들러
Chandler.
두 사람 잘 안 되면
전화해
You call me when this goes
in the pooper.
이 쪽은 내가 맡았어요
I've got this section covered.
사실 이걸로 눈을
부시게 하면...
Yeah, in fact, I've got this baby
to shine in people's eyes.
알았어요, 나중에 봐요
Okay, see you later.
모니카한테
네 책 보여주고 싶어서
I just wanted
to show Monica your book.